Guide to the Gould Colman papers, 1954-1996.
Colman, Gould papers,
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Gould Colman papers, 1954-1996.
13-6-1958
Colman, Gould P. (Gould Patchin), 1926-
7 cubic ft.
Correspondence, Photographs, Printed Materials.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Drafts, interview transcripts and other materials relating to a book project on family farming. Correspondence, materials relating to Rural Sociology courses he taught on Farm Families. Other materials relating to his time as the Cornell University Archivist.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Archivist, historian.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Drafts, interview transcripts and other materials relating to a book project on family farming. Correspondence, materials relating to Rural Sociology courses he taught on Farm Families. Other materials relating to his time as the Cornell University Archivist.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Colman, Gould P. (Gould Patchin), (Gould Patchin), 1926-
Subjects:
Agriculture -- New York (State); Women in agriculture.; Agriculture; Women in agriculture; Farm management -- Case studies.; Farm management -- New York (State); Farm management -- Iowa.; Family farms -- New York (State); Family farms -- Iowa.; Farm life -- History. -- New York (State); Farm life -- History. -- Iowa; Farmers -- Family relationships.; Oral history -- New York (State); Oral history -- Iowa.
Places:
New York (State)
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Farm family interview materials and Residential Club fire folder are restricted to permission of the University Archivist.
NOTES
Also includes #13- -m.705, #21-2-m.401, #47-1-m.569, and #14-2-m.984.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Family Business
a. Interview transcripts
b. Drafts
c. Publication
d. Miscellaneous
Series II. Correspondence
Series III. Lectures, papers, and conference presentations
Series IV. Course materials
Series V. Miscellaneous
CONTAINER LIST
- Family Business, 1966-2011
  - Interview transcripts, 1966-1982
    Interview transcripts have been foldered, but left in original order.
    - Interview transcript excerpts - Reed family, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Restricted to permission of the University Archivist.
    - Interviewer observations - Reed family, 1978-04-01 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Interviewer observations - Jean Reed, 1981-03-19 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Interviewer observations - Susan Reed, 1981-02-17 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Interviewer observations - Jim and Alton Reed, 1981-02-06 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Interviewer observations - Reed family, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Interviewer observations - Reed family, 1974-01-16 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Interviewer observations - Susan Reed, 1974-06-16 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Interviewer observations - Reed family, 1972-02-27 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Interview transcript - Jean Reed, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Interview transcript - Janet Reed, 1969-11 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Interview transcript - James Reed, 1972-01-31 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Interview transcript - Lynn Reed, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Interview transcript - Janet Reed, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Interview transcript - Jean Reed, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Interview transcript - Susan Reed, 1977-01-12 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Interview transcript - Janet Reed, 1977-02-04 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Interview transcript - Jim Reed, 1977-01-12 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Interview transcript - James Reed, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Interview transcript - Reed family, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Interview transcript - Tim Reed, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Interview transcript - Janet Reed, 1974-01-16 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Interview transcript - Janet Reed, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Interview transcript - James Reed, 1981-02-05 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Interview transcript - James Reed, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Interview transcript - Susan Reed-Fanfoni, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Interview transcript - Jean Reed, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Interview transcript - Alton Reed, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Interview transcript - Lynn and Jim Reed, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Interview transcript - Susan Reed, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Interview transcript - Reed family, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Interview transcript - Reed family, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Interview transcript - Laurie Reed, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Interview transcript - Susan Reed, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Interview transcript - James Reed, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Interview transcript - Lynn Reed, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Interview transcript - Lynn Reed, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Interview transcript - James Reed, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Interview transcript - Allen Reed, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Interview transcript - Alton Reed, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Interview transcript - Alton Reed, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Interview transcript - Alton Reed, Undated (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Interview transcript - Alton Reed, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Interview transcript - Alton Reed, Undated (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Interview transcript - Alton Reed, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - "Roberts", Undated (Box 1, Folder 48)
      Empty folder used as a divider.
    - Interview transcript - Chris Lovendahl, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Interview transcript - Chris Lovendahl, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Interview transcript - Albert Lovendahl, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Interview transcript - Alex Lovendahl, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Interview transcript - John Lovendahl, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Interview transcript - Albert Lovendahl, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Interview transcript - Chris Lovendahl, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Interview transcript - Alex Lovendahl, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Interview transcript - Albert Lovendahl, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - Interview transcript - John Lovendahl, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Interview transcript - Chris Lovendahl, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - Interview transcript - Albert Lovendahl, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - Interview transcript - Chris Lovendahl, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - Interview transcript - John Lovendahl, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - Interview transcript - Alex Lovendahl, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 63)
    - Interview transcript - John Lovendahl, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 64)
    - Interview transcript - John and Elaine Lovendahl, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 65)
    - Interview transcript - Alex Lovendahl, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 66)
    - Interview transcript - Albert Lovendahl, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 67)
    - Interview transcript - John Lovendahl, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 68)
    - Interview transcript - Alex Lovendahl, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 69)
    - Interview transcript - Albert Lovendahl, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 70)
    - Interview transcript - Albert Lovendahl, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 71)
    - Interview transcript - Lovendahl family, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 72)
    - Interview transcript - Willard family, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 73)
    - Interview transcript - Jeannie Scott DeGolyer, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 74)
    - Interview transcript - Edith DeGolyer, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 75)
    - Interview transcript - Edith DeGolyer, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 76)
    - Interview transcript - Marydith DeGolyer, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 77)
    - Interview transcript - Alex DeGolyer family, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 78)
    - Interview transcript - DeGolyer family, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 79)
    - Interview transcript - Cal DeGolyer family, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 80)
    - Interview transcript - Maureen DeGolyer, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 81)
    - Interview transcript - Marydith DeGolyer, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 82)
    - Interview transcript - Edith and Ruthlee DeGolyer, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 83)
    - Interview transcript - Avery DeGolyer family, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 84)
    - Interview transcript - Calvin DeGolyer family, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 85)
    - Interview transcript - Willard DeGolyer family, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 86)
    - Interview transcript - Maureen DeGolyer, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 87)
    - Interview transcript - Maureen DeGolyer, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 88)
    - Interview transcript - Marydith DeGolyer, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 89)
    - Interview transcript - Edith DeGolyer, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 90)
    - Interview transcript - Maureen DeGolyer, 1978-01-04 (Box 1, Folder 91)
    - Interview transcript - Marydith DeGolyer, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 92)
    - Interview transcript - Mr. and Mrs. Avery DeGolyer, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 93)
    - Interview transcript - Edith DeGolyer, 1978-01-04 (Box 1, Folder 94)
    - Interview transcript - Edith DeGolyer, 1980-04-11 (Box 1, Folder 95)
    - Interview transcript - Marydith DeGolyer, 1980-02-04 (Box 1, Folder 96)
    - Interview transcript - Marydith DeGolyer, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 97)
    - Interview transcript - Maureen DeGolyer, 1980-04-11 (Box 1, Folder 98)
    - Interview transcript - Maureen DeGolyer, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 99)
    - Interview transcript - Edith DeGolyer, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 100)
    - Interview transcript - Calvin DeGolyer, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 101)
    - Interview transcript - Willard DeGolyer, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 102)
    - Interview transcript - Avery DeGolyer, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 103)
    - Interview transcript - Calvin DeGolyer, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 104)
    - Interview transcript - Willard DeGolyer, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 106)
    - Interview transcript - David DeGolyer, 1982-02-08 (Box 1, Folder 107)
    - Interview transcript - David DeGolyer, 1980-02-04 (Box 1, Folder 108)
    - Interview transcript - Cal DeGolyer, 1980-04-11 (Box 1, Folder 109)
    - Interview transcript - Willard DeGolyer, 1980-04-11 (Box 1, Folder 110)
    - Interview transcript - Willard DeGolyer, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 111)
    - Interview transcript - David DeGolyer, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 112)
    - Interview transcript - A. DeGolyer, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 113)
    - Interview transcript - Cal DeGolyer, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 114)
    - Interview transcript - Willard DeGolyer, 1975-02-27 (Box 1, Folder 115)
    - Interview transcript - David DeGolyer, 1975-01-13 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Interview transcript - A. DeGolyer, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Interview transcript - Cal DeGolyer, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Interview transcript - David DeGolyer, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Interview transcript - Willard DeGolyer, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Interview transcript - Cal DeGolyer, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Interview transcript - Avery DeGolyer, 1973-03-13 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Interview transcript - W. DeGolyer, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Interview transcript - Calvin DeGolyer, 1971-01-21 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Interview transcript - Avery DeGolyer, 1971-04-08 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Interview transcript - Calvin DeGolyer, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - "Lovendahls", Undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Interview transcript - Willis Grimmius, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Interview transcript - Willis Grimmius, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Interview transcript - Ruth Grimmius, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Interview transcript - Louise Grimmius, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Interview transcript - Louise Grimmius, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Interview transcript - Eileen Flater, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Interview transcript - Eileen Flater, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Interview transcript - Dale Grimmius, 1982-06-23 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Interview transcript - Walter Grimmius, Undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Interview transcript - Helen Grimmius, Undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Interview transcript - Pat Flater, Undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Interview transcript - David Grimmius, Undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Interview transcript - Rachel Grimmius, Undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Interview transcript - Walter Grimmius, Undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Interview transcript - Rachel Grimmius, Undated (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Interview transcript - Willis Grimmius, 1978-07-19 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Interview transcript - Walter Grimmius, Undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Interview transcript - Ray Flater, Undated (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Interview transcript - Pat Flater, Undated (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Interview transcript - David Grimmius, Undated (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Interview transcript - Helen Grimmius, Undated (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Interview transcript - Ron Flater, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Interview transcript - Ron Flater, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Drafts, 1968-2011
    - "Draft, Master Copy", 1983-03-01 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - The Lovendahls outline, 1984-06-12 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - "Stegmeyer" outline, Undated (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - "Roberts" chapter draft 2, Undated (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - "The Farm Needs Everyone" second draft, 1984-05-03 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Sarah's review of drafts, Undated (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Sarah's critique, 1983-10-28 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - "Our Farm Needs Everybody" first draft, 1983-10-28 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Draft, Chapter 1, 1984-01-01 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Chapter 1, Farming, 1984-04-15 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - "The Brothers" draft, 1984-06-20 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Comments on Puryear cases of DeGolyer, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - "Farming" draft, 1982-11-16 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - "Farming" draft, 1982-11-08 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - "Making Decisions in Farm Families: A Framework for Analysis", Undated (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - "Farming" draft, 1983-01-01 (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - "Lovendahl" excerpts, 1968-1982 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - "Farming" draft, 1983-03-17 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - "A Conflict of Cultures" draft, Undated (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - "The Brothers" draft, 1985-01-15 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - "The Brothers" draft, 1984-11-15 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Lovendahl epilogue, Undated (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - Introduction notes, Undated (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - "Family Business" draft, Undated (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - Miscellaneous notes and draft pages, Undated (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - "Inside Farming" notes, 1989-01-30 (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - Miscellaneous draft pages, Undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Draft pages, Undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Preface "A Different Way of Doing Business" draft, 1987-01-12 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Draft pages and notes, Undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Book review draft, Undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - "Farming: Another Way of Doing Business" draft, Undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - "Farming: Another Way of Doing Business" final draft, Undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Draft pages and notes, Undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - "This Farm Needs Everyone" second draft, 1984-01-01 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - "Our Farm Needs Everybody" draft with comments, 1983-10-28 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Safety copy draft, 1985-03-18 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - "Farm Families in Double Jeopardy" draft, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - "Farming Families: The Farm Needs Everyone", Undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - "Notes", Undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - "Farming" draft with comments and notes, 1983-01-01 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - "Farming" drafts, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - "The Brothers" third draft, Undated (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - "The Brothers" second draft, 1985-01-15 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - "Chapter III: Doing It" draft, Undated (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - "Introduction" draft, 1990-02-26 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - "Introduction" drafts, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - "Family Business" draft, 2011-04-11 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - "Introduction" drafts and comments, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Chapter 3 revision, 1989-12 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Chapter III extra copy, 1990-03-15 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - "The Brothers" draft, 1990-02-24 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - "The Brothers" draft, 1985-01-15 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - "Introduction" draft, 1985-03-18 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - "Chapter II: The Farm Needs Everyone" draft, 1985-04-04 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - "The Brothers" draft, Undated (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - "Chapter II: The Farm Needs Everyone" draft, Undated (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - "Chapter III: Doing It" draft, Undated (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - "The Farm Needs Everyone" draft, 1990-02-13 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - "Inside Farming" Intro and Chapter 1 draft, 1990-01-12 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - "Chapter II: Farm Needs Everyone", 1989-11-08 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - "The Brothers" and "Intro", 1989-09-15 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - "Chapter II: The Farm Needs Everyone" draft, Undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Chapter II revised draft, 1989-11-08 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - "The Brothers" draft, 1989-08-01 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - "Inside Farming" draft with second revisions, 1989-06-01 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - "The Brothers" revised draft, Undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - "Chapter III: Doing It" draft, Undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - "Farming: A Different Way of Doing Business" unpublished draft, 1986-07-22 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - "Farming: Introduction" unpublished draft, 1987-01-12 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - "The Farm Needs Everyone" draft, 1990-02-13 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - "The Farm Needs Everyone" draft, 1991-04-10 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - "The Farm Needs Everyone" draft, 1993-02 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - "The Farm Needs Everyone" revised draft, 1993-04-24 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - "The Farm Needs Everyone" revised draft, 1993-05-11 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - "The Farm Needs Everyone" revised draft, 1993-05-20 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - "The Farm Needs Everyone" revised draft, 1994-04-01 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - "The Farm Needs Everyone" revised draft, 1994-04-30 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - "The Farm Needs Everyone" revised draft, 1994-11-15 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - "The Farm Needs Everyone" draft, 1994-12-14 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - "The Farm Needs Everyone" draft, 1993-03-30 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - "The Farm Needs Everyone" draft, 1994-11-15 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - "The Farm Needs Everyone" draft, Undated (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - "Farming" draft fragments, 1993-04-12 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - "Farming" draft fragments, Undated (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - "Farming" draft fragments, 1993-03-02 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - "The Farm Needs Everyone" draft, 1993-02-11 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - "Farming" draft fragments, Undated (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - "The Farm Needs Everyone" draft, 1993-01-20 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - "The Farm Needs Everyone" draft, 1993-01-10 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - "The Brothers" draft, 1990-02-24 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - "The Brothers" draft, 1991-01-15 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - "The Brothers" draft, 1992-01-18 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - "The Brothers" draft, 1992-05-01 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - "The Brothers" draft, 1992-07-17 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - "The Brothers" draft, 1992-12-02 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - "The Brothers" draft, 1992-12-06 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - "The Brothers" draft, 1992-12-24 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - "The Brothers" draft, 1993-01-04 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - "The Brothers" draft with Chris Engst comments, 1993-01-04 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - "The Brothers" draft, 1993-06-24 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - "The Brothers" draft, 1994-04-15 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - "The Brothers" draft, 1994-07-10 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - "The Brothers" draft, 1994-12-20 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - "The Brothers" draft, 1995-01-10 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - "The Brothers" draft, 1995-01-16 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - "The Brothers" draft, 1995-01-20 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - "The Brothers" draft, Undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - "The Brothers" draft fragments, 1991-1992 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - "Doing It" draft, 1991-03-15 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - "Doing It" draft, 1991-04-30 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - "Doing It" draft, 1991-04-30 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - "Doing It" draft, 1994-05-01 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - "Doing It" draft, 1994-04-22 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - "Doing It" draft, 1994-03-15 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - "Doing It" draft, 1994-04-10 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - "Doing It" draft, 1995-01-27 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - "Doing It" draft, 1995-02-02 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Intro and Conclusion various drafts, 1990-1991 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Intro and Conclusion various drafts, 1991-1995 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - "Farming" complete draft, 1987-01-12 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - "Privileged Work" complete draft, 1991-04-10 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Chapters 1 and 2 complete drafts, 1993-10-08 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - "Farming" feedback, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Comments on "Farming", 1987 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Comments on "final" draft, 1985-04 (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - "Family Business" draft pages, Undated (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - "Farm Family Book" draft, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - Farm families book draft, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Publication, 1987-1990
    - Letter to Sheldon Meyer, Editor, Oxford University Press, 1990-11-16 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence with publishers, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous, 1970-1988
    - "Farm Family Financial Situation", 1972 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - "TRE, Inc. For Credit File", 1979-01-01 (Box 1, Folder 105)
    - "The Farm Quarterly" article photocopy, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - "Why we can’t trust the news media" article photocopy, 1984-01-13 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Memo and DeGolyer family data surveys, 1981-09-15 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - "Resources for Working with Farm Families", 1988-01-04 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Farm family notes, 1972-01 (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - Farm family interview questions, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - Interviewer questions and notes; interviewer comments, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - 1981-1982 interview questions, Undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Farm family oral history project form question responses, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 36)
    - "Oral History Problems and Procedures", Undated (Box 7, Folder 42)
- Correspondence, Spring
  - Summary of selected publications, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Memos to Indian Studies Advisory Committee, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence with Sarah Elbert, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence with Sarah Elbert, Undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - General correspondence, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - General correspondence, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence with Sarah Elbert, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - General correspondence, 1986-1987 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Bjergo letters of recommendation, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - General correspondence, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - General correspondence, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - General correspondence, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - General correspondence, 1982-1983 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - General correspondence, 1982-1983 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - General correspondence, 1981-1982 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - General correspondence, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - General correspondence, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - General correspondence, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 53)
  - Correspondence with Sarah Elbert, 1981-1983 (Box 6, Folder 55)
  - Board of Trustees correspondence, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 39)
- Lectures, papers, and conference presentations, 1961-1987
  - Rural Studies Group Fall Seminar Series syllabus, Undated (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - American Farm Women Conference seminar participants list, 1984-02-04 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - "The Farmer Takes a Wife: Women in America's Farming Families" by Sarah Elbert, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - "Amber Waves of Gain: Women's Work in New York Families" by Sarah Elbert, Undated (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - "Contented Cows and Dairy Maids: Patriarchy and Capitalism in American Agriculture" by Sarah Elbert, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - "Farming Families: The Farm Needs Everyone" by Gould Colman and Sarah Elbert, Undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - "A Real Ranch" with comments, Undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
    No author listed, but possibly by Allen Bjergo and Tom Ruffatto.
  - "Ranching", 1987-06 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - List of participants, Kellogg Workshop, 1987-11 (Box 6, Folder 17)